# **AUSTIN DOWNEY**

Location: Boise, Idaho Cell: 2082508543 Email: <a href="mailto:austinjdowney@gmail.com">austinjdowney@gmail.com</a> LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/austindowney@gmail.com">https://www.linkedin.com/in/austindowney@gmail.com</a> LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/austinjdowney@gmail.com">https://www.linkedin.com/in/austinjdowney@gmail.com</a> LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/austinjdowney@gmail.com">https://www.linkedin.com/austinjdowney@gmail.com</a> LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/austinjdowney@gmail.com">https://

### **OBJECTIVE**

A full-stack software developer with knowledge in multiple different coding stacks (i.e., Vue.js, Node.js, C#) with an ability to adapt different concepts on the fly, which includes incorporating my psychology background to provide an emphasis on the user experience (UX). Passionate about full-stack development and watching an application come to life from the beginning.

## **SKILLS**

JavaScript (Vue3.js) - MONGO DB - Node.js - C#

SCSS - J QUERY - RESTful Api - .Net

Bootstrap - Agile SCRUM - Auth0 - MySQL

### **EXPERIENCE**

# SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT STUDENT, BOISE CODEWORKS, 3/2021 - PRESENT

- Fast paced full-stack software development learning
- Agile SCRUM approach to application building focusing on time and team management

### SERVER/TOGO SPECIALIST, OLIVE GARDEN, 5/2015 - 11/2017; 6/2019 - PRESENT

- Providing customers with exemplary and efficient restaurant service based upon Olive Garden's high standards of excellence. Time and task management is a high priority to achieve the high-level of standards placed upon Olive Garden and expected by guests.

### FITNESS COUNSELOR, AXIOM FITNESS, 8/2017 - 7/2019

- Qualify potential members both by the individual but also business to business, to identify what goals they are
  looking for health wise and see based on what they are looking for in a fitness facility and their financial means.
- Lead Fitness Counselor, 10/2018 7/2019
  - Overseeing Fitness Consultants for optimal sales approaches, in order to meet optimal sales goals for both the company and the FC's, individually, based on their own characteristics and financial needs.

# COMMUNITY- BASED REHABILITATION WORKER, KUNA COUNSELING CENTER, 9/2015 – 10/2016

Worked with a variety of demographics on coping skills and life skills that are unique and individualized for when
those individuals have a trigger. In conjunction with this, working in a clinical setting with insurance companies on
providing coverage for these individuals until they can be self-sustaining.

# **CAMPUS COORDINATOR/BELLTOWER BUYER (PACIFIC UNIVERSITY),** BELLTOWER BOOKS, 11/2012-06/2015

- Promoted to Campus Coordinator, 3/2013 6/2015)
- Main role was to recruit and evaluate potential employees, but also the management and oversight of these same employees. The job entails the Belltower Buyers to buy any type of used book (i.e., textbooks, novels, children books, etc.), and ensuring the Belltower buyers were exchanging the proper amount of cash for each book. Another aspect related to being a Campus Coordinator was the advertisement of not only job opportunities for Belltower Books, but the advertisement of current popular deals and events for Belltower Books.

### **EDUCATION**

# **CERTIFICATE OF SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT**, BOISE CODEWORKS, SPRING COHORT 2021 **B.S. PSYCHOLOGY WITH A MINOR IN SOCIOLOGY,** PACIFIC UNIVERSITY, CLASS 2015

- Emphasis on neuroscience with clinical disorders

# VOLUNTEERING

# ALTERNATIVE SPRING BREAK THRU PACIFIC UNIVERSITY

- Volunteering in San Francisco with various homeless populations and shelters (40 hours volunteering, March 2013)

## PACIFIC UNIVERSITY AMBASSADOR

- Fall 2012 – Spring 2014

# **APPLICATIONS**

### **KEEPR**

- Full-stack application that was developed in a week that has been described as similar to Pinterest.
  - Incorporates Vue.js, C#, Bootstrap, SASS, Auth0, J Query, SCRUM, and MySql.
  - Application incorporates multiple different style relationships (i.e., one to one, one to many, and many to many)
  - A user is able to create their own vaults and keeps, which are used to add to certain individual vaults.
  - Keeps are tracked by the number of times views and "kept" in individual vaults.
  - Users are able to add another user's keeps to their own vault (i.e., vaultKeeps) and is able to delete them once added to a vault.
  - Users are able to view another user's profile, which contains their own public vaults and keeps, but a user does have the option to make a vault private upon creation, which hides it from other users.

## CarbonNone (Carbon Footprint app)

- Full-stack application within a group of 4 developers completed in just under 2 weeks.
  - Incorporated Vue.js, Node.js, SCSS, Bootstrap, 3 RESTful Api's, Auth0, J Query, Chart.js and SRUM
  - Application is a carbon emissions tracker for your house (i.e., electric and water usage), bike/walk miles to help
    encourage other modes of carbon free emissions, and car(s) that incorporate varying gas types that will
    influence your emissions (i.e., unleaded, diesel, hybrid) in relation to miles driven.
  - Able to track your own emissions relative to the national average.
  - Able to see your daily score and your last 7 daily emissions on your own and other user's profiles.
  - Able to see a daily update of carbon emission news and air quality, based on your current location, on the home page.

### **BUGLOGGER**

- First full-stack individual application incorporating Vue.js, Node.js, Bootstrap, SASS, Auth0, and J QUERY.
  - Able to create "bugs"/data and then be pushed to that "bugs" details page to edit (only for the "bug" creator) that "bugs" information.
  - All users can create notes related to that specific "bug."
  - Included differing rules where one could not delete a "bug" fully, the status would just switch from open/close, but if you created a note on that "bug" you would be able to delete that note
  - Additionally, be able to filter the closed "bugs" off the page and keep only the open "bugs."

# **KANBAN**

- First full-stack partner developed application incorporating Vue.js, Node.js, Bootstrap, SASS, J Query, AuthO, and SCRUM.
  - An application geared towards the private organization of TODO lists, interests, inventory of materials, and more.
  - An individual is able to create a "board" where you are able to make an infinite number of lists related to that "board."
  - Create cascading tasks based off those lists, and furthermore be able to leave comments or reminders to help complete your lists and tasks.

# **INSPIRE**

- Application designed within the first 4 weeks of coding with RESTful Api's incorporating 4 different end points and a real time customized clock.
  - Background images from UNSPLASH that on refresh would change to a different HD randomized image.
  - Randomized inspirational quotes that would also change on refresh, which also had the author hidden unless the pointer was on hover.
  - Weather temperature was included in Fahrenheit based off the city, state you were located in.
  - Task Manager to add tasks and then be able to track how many tasks were completed, relative to total amount of tasks, but upon completion would also include a strike through.

Page | 2 Austin Downey